<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Equity | Most Significant Byte]]></title>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/categories/equity/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2016-02-22T23:14:52-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devin Hurley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Equity]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2016/02/21/how-to-equity/"/>
    <updated>2016-02-21T14:36:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2016/02/21/how-to-equity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="hark-an-angel">Hark! An Angel!</h2>

<p>So recently I’ve had to do a little math as to how to value my stock options as a part of my total equity package.  Below I will outline an equation 
which will approximate the optimal stock options grant you should receive based on the risk you take by joining a startup (this risk is variable based on where in 
the funding timeline your company is) along with the investment you make should you need to take an undermarket salary, along with and a few other things to take 
into consideration.</p>

<p>Being purely logical, the output of this equation is what you should expect.  Most founders will not offer you this but this is a great tool to help get a 
general understanding of what you’re giving up when you take on an under market salary in exchange for equity.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>After doing an explicit example (with a bit of help from a stranger on the Internet) I generalized my specific outcomes so that it could help others who find themselves in similar situations.</p>

<p>The beauty of the following equation is that almost all of these numbers are numbers that the people on the other side of the table have to come up with.
The logic that follows is simple and even better, allows the everyone to reach the same logical conclusion.  YMMV.</p>

<h2 id="how-to-101-market-rate-salary">How to 101: Market Rate Salary</h2>

<p>Let’s say you’re interviewing at a startup and the company offers you some salary POST-TAX which we will call <script type="math/tex">s_{0}</script>, and options.  Given that salary, how do 
you come up with an appropriate amount of options that will givey you a return on the investment of an undermarket salary along with the risk of joining an early 
(pre series A) startup?  </p>

<p>Let’s say a market salary for your position (POST-TAX) is <script type="math/tex">s_{m}</script>.  Pick whatever number suits you but to explain the equation I will start with this number.<br />
Assuming you work at this startup for <script type="math/tex">N</script> years you will give up approximately…  </p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N]
</script>

<p>in salary.  This step is important, so take some time and really try to simulate just how much salary you are giving up.  Your market rate should jump every year
 or so as the rate at which you learn at a startup is exponentially faster than at BigCo.<br />
So to figure out how much equity you would need to make up for that loss of salary, you would just take that number, divide it by the startup’s optimal outcome,
which we will call <script type="math/tex">\Omega</script> (say the company sells for 18 Billion <code>USD</code>, <script type="math/tex">\Omega \equiv 18\,Billion</script>), and now you’re done!</p>

<p>… Except you probably haven’t filed an 83b, subject to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alternative_minimum_tax">AMT</a> which in the U.S. is approximately 35% so you’ll want to account for that in your calculation</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
\frac{[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N] \cdot (1.35)}{\Omega}
</script>

<p>You should also consider the strike price for these options as well, as you will need to spend your salary to purchase those, and include some dilution factor (a conservative value is 25% over 4 years, which is 6.25% per year so you’ll need to calculate that by hand to really figure out what constant to use.  Let’s up this value to <script type="math/tex">1.60</script> to help insulate us from this.  Now that we know what we need AT EXIT, we’re all set? Right? Right?!?! </p>

<h2 id="exit-to-the-right-of-the-aircraft">Exit to the Right of the Aircraft</h2>

<p>So given our optimal outcome <script type="math/tex">\Omega</script> we need to calculate the risk of not hitting that target.  Instead of using this pure value we should weight it according to the probability of <script type="math/tex">\Omega</script> actually occurring.  Our expected outcome will now be <script type="math/tex">p(\Omega) \cdot \Omega</script>.  So our new equation for our necessary equity becomes…</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
\frac{[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N] \cdot (1.60)}{p(\Omega) \cdot \Omega}
</script>

<p>This will give us a nice buffer in case we miss this optimal target.  HOWEVER THIS IS STILL JUST TO BREAK EVEN.
The idea is to get a nice upside for lowering your standard of living for <script type="math/tex">N</script> years along with the increased stress and work necessary for helping to build a company.  SO, let’s double this value</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
2 \cdot \left (\frac{[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N] \cdot (1.60)}{p(\Omega)\cdot\Omega}  \right )
</script>

<p>This will represent how much (logically) you would be within your right to ask for. </p>

<p>To calculate how much this percent will represent after debt is paid down and taking into account the preferred shareholders stake (assuming this represents about 25% of the pie), I’m assuming 25% of the outcome  will go to preferred stock holders and other forms of debt, before it reaches ESOs.</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
0.75 \cdot \left (2 \cdot \left (\frac{[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N] \cdot (1.60)}{p(\Omega)\cdot\Omega}  \right ) \right )
</script>

<p>This equation will approximate how much of the company you will truly own by the time your company exits.</p>

<h3 id="tldr">TL;DR</h3>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">0.75 \equiv Percent\, common\, stock\, options\, represent\, out\, of\, total\, options\, pool. </script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">2 \equiv Upside</script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">s_{m} \equiv Market\, salary\, for\, your\, position.</script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">s_{0} \equiv Salary\, offered.</script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">1.60 \equiv AMT\, and\, 6.25%\, dilution\, /\, annum.</script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">\Omega \equiv Outcome\, of\, Exit</script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">p(\Omega) \equiv Probability\, of\, outcome.</script>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">
2 \cdot \left (\frac{[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N] \cdot (1.60)}{p(\Omega)\cdot\Omega}  \right ) \equiv How\, many\, points\, to\, ask\, for
</script>

<p>… and finally, what you can reasonable expect your points to represent out of the total <script type="math/tex">\Omega</script> left over after debt and prefferred shareholders get their 
slice …
<script type="math/tex">
0.75 \cdot \left (2 \cdot \left (\frac{[(s_{m} - s_{0}) \cdot N] \cdot (1.60)}{p(\Omega)\cdot\Omega}  \right ) \right )
</script></p>

<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>You should never join a startup because you want to be rich.  Join one because you will have responsibilities you would have to wait 10+ years to have; join one 
because you like the people that started the company;  join one because you will be forced to jump out of your comfort zone; join one because you want to test
yourself.  Do not join one if your dream is to get rich.  There are far easier and safer ways to do this.  However, there should be decent payout for the fact that you did take a risk, imbued some amount of 
increased stress, and possibly damaged a few relationships along the way.</p>

<p>The obvious objective is to secure a market salary in the first place.  At this point any options would simply be icing on the proverbial cake.  However sometimes 
this is not possible so you have to take a salary cut.  This post is designed to help you as an early startup employee prevent yourself from becoming <a href="http://www.nytimes.com/2015/12/27/technology/when-a-unicorn-start-up-stumbles-its-employees-get-hurt.html?_r=0">one</a> of <a href="http://blog.nawbo-sv.org/incentive-stock-option-horror-story/">these</a> other <a href="http://venturebeat.com/2012/02/27/a-classic-startup-horror-story-the-ma-bait-and-switch/">guys</a></p>

<p>I hope this helps some people out there with difficult decisions to make.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
