<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Coding | Most Significant Byte]]></title>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/categories/coding/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-27T14:27:38-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devin Hurley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What I Learned at POMCO Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/11/11/what-i-learned-at-pomco-today/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-11T13:21:37-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/11/11/what-i-learned-at-pomco-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="introduction">Introduction</h3>

<p>People say you learn a lot at a good startup (even if you’re at a crappy startup, you can still take the time to invest in yourself).
I wanted to start a series of blog posts chronicling what I learn, whether in the vein of technology or simple and general life skills, in
the hope that these lessons may be applicable to someone who discovers this blog on the Internet.  </p>

<p>My first lesson I would like to present is about..</p>

<h4 id="the-long-primitive-in-objective-c">The ‘long’ primitive in Objective-C</h4>

<p>The ANSI C-Standard calls for a MINIMUM of <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/a/589684">4 bytes for a long</a>.  However it does not set a maximum.  This is important because
the iPhone 6 and 6S use a long value of 8 bytes, whereas all other iPhones use long values of 4 bytes.  So if you ever create a long that, when printed,
is the correct number on the iPhone 6 or 6S but not on any other previous generation, it’s because your long is not long enough.  You need to use <code>long long</code>.</p>

<p>I learned about this because I was getting the Unix Epoch time and trying to convert that into time since January 1st, 1900.  So when I did the conversion on my 
iPhone 6, the <code>long</code> was able to hold the proper value.  However on any other iOS device predating the iPhone 6, this number would wrap around to negative values
because it was larger than 4 bytes could store.</p>

<p>So kids, remember to run your tests on all the different simulators and devices!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
