<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wsj | Most Significant Byte]]></title>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/categories/wsj/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2017-10-30T22:48:51-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devin Hurley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WSJ3: Russia and Saudi Arabia to Continue Pumping Oil]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/10/07/wsj3-russia-and-saudi-arabia-to-continue-pumping-oil/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-07T20:40:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/10/07/wsj3-russia-and-saudi-arabia-to-continue-pumping-oil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="by-georgi-kantchev-and-summer-said-october-3rd-2015">By Georgi Kantchev and Summer Said (October 3rd, 2015)</h3>

<h3 id="article-summary">Article Summary</h3>

<p>Russia is aggressively pumping oil from its wells at a rate of 10.74 million barrels a day.  Saudi Arabia will continue to pump oil and gas at a rate above 10 million barrels a day, which has continued to fuel the significant drop in oil prices.  Oil prices have dropped &gt; 50% since July of 2014.  Supply outpaces demand globally by approximately 2 million barrels a day.  The IMF expects the Saudi government will run a budget deficit of 19.5% of GDP.  Last year the Saudi government’s deficit was 3.4% of GDP.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The increase in the global supply of oil has left nations such as Venezuela and Nigeria, who are dependent on oil revenue, flailing to keep their finances in line.  The depreciation of the ruble has left oil companies in Russia a better margin buffer than American-based shale companies.  The level of output Russia is expected to produce this year was last seen at the end of the Soviet Union.</p>

<h2 id="analysis">Analysis</h2>

<p>Russia and Saudi Arabia are launching a type of economic war against the greater global economy (despite the detrimental effects this will have for their own economies).  This is aiding a global slowdown in demand, since oil and gas contribute to the production of goods.  As oil prices fall oil companies begin pulling back on investments.  Specifically, American shale companies have shut down and laid off thousands.  Offshore drilling companies have had their own layoffs to deal with as their margins shrank abruptly.  This has ripple effects in industries that produce materials for the maintenance and construction of oil rigs.  With Russia and Saudi Arabia oversupplying the globe with crude, businesses in the industry are forced to downsize drastically.</p>

<p>America needs greater independence from oil producing nations.  These nations are the true achilles heel to America’s economic stability.  Investments in alternative sources of energy by the government would placate the effects the Russians and Saudis are having on America’s future growth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WSJ2: China's President Courts U.S. CEOs]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/09/28/wsj2-chinas-president-courts-u-dot-s-ceos/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-28T22:47:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/09/28/wsj2-chinas-president-courts-u-dot-s-ceos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="chinas-president-courts-us-ceos">China’s President Courts U.S. CEOs</h3>

<h4 id="by-shira-ovide-and-jeremy-page">By Shira Ovide and Jeremy Page</h4>

<p>President Xi Jinping is looking to increase investment in China through promoting China’s increased demand.  U.S. companies have long been wary of exporting goods to China due to lacking intellectual property laws and general market access.
President Xi Jinping seeks lower restrictions in his country to allow for the U.S. to increase high-tech exports to China, as well as lowering the barries to investment in general in the nation.
Mr. Xi gave a speech outlining all of this after a conference with CEOs from Chinese and U.S. corporations.  Among the people present were Tim Cook, Satya Nadella and Jeff Bezos.  High-tech Chinese companies including Jack Ma (Alibaba), Pony Ma (Tencent Holdings) and Robin Li (Baidu) were also in attendance.  Mr. Xi’s claims China’s allure for high-tech U.S. companies should be the huge population that utilizes internet connected devices.  Mr. Xi says China is home to 600 million Internet users and 1.2 billion mobile phone users.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Such a large market for consumer electronic devices and China’s seemingly wholehearted approach to economic openness and increased free trade should have companies jumping at China’s heels.  Unfortunately for the general Chinese populace, their government has been behind some massive attacks on U.S. companies, most recently and dramatically the attack on <a href="http://blog.erratasec.com/2015/04/pin-pointing-chinas-attack-against.html">GitHub</a>.
The general attacks on U.S. companies by the Chinese and other worries, such as intellectual property theft and determining whether the market demand actually exists for consumer electronics has kept U.S. companies steadfast in their cautious approach to expanding to The Far East.  It is this author’s opinion that this move by Mr. Xi was in fact an appeal to the nations at large that China’s economy is not propped up by massive IPOs and the government, but a natural demand flows within the nation.  Through increasing foreign investment into China, China no longer has to prop up its economy and can rely on foreign investment to do the dirty work.  If U.S. companies do bite, China will be forced to buy more U.S. dollars (so that China can purchase U.S. goods), forcing the dollar to rise in purchasing power.  Kind of like what happened with Germany and the Euro.</p>

<p>A weak currency generally allows for a nations’ exports to become cheaper.  When a nation has more exports than imports, it is said to have a surplus.  How do countries devalue their currency so that it does not become so expensive that it’s citizens can no longer afford to own it? By “printing” more of it and flooding the market!  However, the Eurozone has not done this.  Instead as it (Germany specifically) exported more and more, it did not try to keep the currency at a lower exchange rate (as Greece, Spain, Italy etc. would have preferred it) and allowed it to increase in strength.  This was great for Germany.  As its’ goods became more expensive to purchase while exports continued to flow out of the country, Germany racked up a trade surplus and a stronger currency. Greece, Italy, Portugal, Spain and a host of other countries that depended on the Euro got pushed into the mud at the expense of Germany’s power grab. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
