<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Economics | Most Significant Byte]]></title>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/categories/economics/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-28T11:57:11-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Devin Hurley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WSJ3: Russia and Saudi Arabia to Continue Pumping Oil]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/10/07/wsj3-russia-and-saudi-arabia-to-continue-pumping-oil/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-07T20:40:12-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/10/07/wsj3-russia-and-saudi-arabia-to-continue-pumping-oil</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="by-georgi-kantchev-and-summer-said-october-3rd-2015">By Georgi Kantchev and Summer Said (October 3rd, 2015)</h3>

<h3 id="article-summary">Article Summary</h3>

<p>Russia is aggressively pumping oil from its wells at a rate of 10.74 million barrels a day.  Saudi Arabia will continue to pump oil and gas at a rate above 10 million barrels a day, which has continued to fuel the significant drop in oil prices.  Oil prices have dropped &gt; 50% since July of 2014.  Supply outpaces demand globally by approximately 2 million barrels a day.  The IMF expects the Saudi government will run a budget deficit of 19.5% of GDP.  Last year the Saudi government’s deficit was 3.4% of GDP.
<!--more--></p>

<p>The increase in the global supply of oil has left nations such as Venezuela and Nigeria, who are dependent on oil revenue, flailing to keep their finances in line.  The depreciation of the ruble has left oil companies in Russia a better margin buffer than American-based shale companies.  The level of output Russia is expected to produce this year was last seen at the end of the Soviet Union.</p>

<h2 id="analysis">Analysis</h2>

<p>Russia and Saudi Arabia are launching a type of economic war against the greater global economy (despite the detrimental effects this will have for their own economies).  This is aiding a global slowdown in demand, since oil and gas contribute to the production of goods.  As oil prices fall oil companies begin pulling back on investments.  Specifically, American shale companies have shut down and laid off thousands.  Offshore drilling companies have had their own layoffs to deal with as their margins shrank abruptly.  This has ripple effects in industries that produce materials for the maintenance and construction of oil rigs.  With Russia and Saudi Arabia oversupplying the globe with crude, businesses in the industry are forced to downsize drastically.</p>

<p>America needs greater independence from oil producing nations.  These nations are the true achilles heel to America’s economic stability.  Investments in alternative sources of energy by the government would placate the effects the Russians and Saudis are having on America’s future growth.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[WSJ2: China's President Courts U.S. CEOs]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/09/28/wsj2-chinas-president-courts-u-dot-s-ceos/"/>
    <updated>2015-09-28T22:47:49-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/09/28/wsj2-chinas-president-courts-u-dot-s-ceos</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="chinas-president-courts-us-ceos">China’s President Courts U.S. CEOs</h3>

<h4 id="by-shira-ovide-and-jeremy-page">By Shira Ovide and Jeremy Page</h4>

<p>President Xi Jinping is looking to increase investment in China through promoting China’s increased demand.  U.S. companies have long been wary of exporting goods to China due to lacking intellectual property laws and general market access.
President Xi Jinping seeks lower restrictions in his country to allow for the U.S. to increase high-tech exports to China, as well as lowering the barries to investment in general in the nation.
Mr. Xi gave a speech outlining all of this after a conference with CEOs from Chinese and U.S. corporations.  Among the people present were Tim Cook, Satya Nadella and Jeff Bezos.  High-tech Chinese companies including Jack Ma (Alibaba), Pony Ma (Tencent Holdings) and Robin Li (Baidu) were also in attendance.  Mr. Xi’s claims China’s allure for high-tech U.S. companies should be the huge population that utilizes internet connected devices.  Mr. Xi says China is home to 600 million Internet users and 1.2 billion mobile phone users.
<!--more--></p>

<p>Such a large market for consumer electronic devices and China’s seemingly wholehearted approach to economic openness and increased free trade should have companies jumping at China’s heels.  Unfortunately for the general Chinese populace, their government has been behind some massive attacks on U.S. companies, most recently and dramatically the attack on <a href="http://blog.erratasec.com/2015/04/pin-pointing-chinas-attack-against.html">GitHub</a>.
The general attacks on U.S. companies by the Chinese and other worries, such as intellectual property theft and determining whether the market demand actually exists for consumer electronics has kept U.S. companies steadfast in their cautious approach to expanding to The Far East.  It is this author’s opinion that this move by Mr. Xi was in fact an appeal to the nations at large that China’s economy is not propped up by massive IPOs and the government, but a natural demand flows within the nation.  Through increasing foreign investment into China, China no longer has to prop up its economy and can rely on foreign investment to do the dirty work.  If U.S. companies do bite, China will be forced to buy more U.S. dollars (so that China can purchase U.S. goods), forcing the dollar to rise in purchasing power.  Kind of like what happened with Germany and the Euro.</p>

<p>A weak currency generally allows for a nations’ exports to become cheaper.  When a nation has more exports than imports, it is said to have a surplus.  How do countries devalue their currency so that it does not become so expensive that it’s citizens can no longer afford to own it? By “printing” more of it and flooding the market!  However, the Eurozone has not done this.  Instead as it (Germany specifically) exported more and more, it did not try to keep the currency at a lower exchange rate (as Greece, Spain, Italy etc. would have preferred it) and allowed it to increase in strength.  This was great for Germany.  As its’ goods became more expensive to purchase while exports continued to flow out of the country, Germany racked up a trade surplus and a stronger currency. Greece, Italy, Portugal, Spain and a host of other countries that depended on the Euro got pushed into the mud at the expense of Germany’s power grab. </p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Bidding Up Tech Shares]]></title>
    <link href="http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/07/25/on-bidding-up-tech-shares/"/>
    <updated>2015-07-25T11:54:42-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://dhurley14.github.io/blog/2015/07/25/on-bidding-up-tech-shares</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="background">Background</h2>
<ol>
  <li>Googles’ shares rose 16% on Friday (2015-07-17) after the company said revenue was up 11% from a year earlier.</li>
  <li>Netflix rose 18% on Thursday (2015-07-16) after 2nd quarter revenue rose 22%</li>
  <li>Amazon announced it’s revenue on Thursday (2015-07-23) had risen 20%, resulting in a record high price on Friday of $580.57.</li>
  <li>Facebook is expected to announce its earnings on the 29th of July.</li>
  <li>The Nasdaq is up 10% this year, reaching a new record on Friday (2015-07-17).</li>
</ol>

<p>Looks pretty good for the technology sector.  The rest of the sectors ain’t doing so hot though..
<!--more--></p>

<h2 id="whats-a-poor-boy-to-do">What’s a poor boy to do?</h2>
<p>The Nasdaq’s rise is a result of the percentage of tech stocks that make up the index.  Compare this to the S&amp;P500, which rose
3.3% this year and still remains below highs reached in May.  Given approximately 50% of the composition of the Nasdaq index is made up of tech companies
while the S&amp;P 500 is made up of ~20% tech stocks, there is evidence of an impending tech bubble for these public stocks.  But is it really a bubble?</p>

<p>The evidence to look for lies in the lack of high-achieving performance in the wider economy.  Sales and earnings in many sectors of 
the economy are flat or falling, making investment in tech stocks mroe appealing than they previously (&lt; 2000 A.D.) were.</p>

<p>Many portfolio managers say they are willing to pay such high prices for these tech stocks because their (the managers’) expectations of growth
for the tech companies outweighs the up-front costs to owning these shares.  Growth is becoming more scarce in the global economy.
Quarterly revenue at S&amp;P500 companies is estimated to have dropped 4% from a year ago in the 2nd quarter (via FactSet).</p>

<p>For example, Google shares have been trading at 24.9x last 12 months earnings;  Netflix is trading at 257.8x 12 months’ earnings and Facebook
is trading at 52.5x.</p>

<p>The wide availability of V.C. funding for smaller, faster-growing companies allows these companies to stay private for far longer.  Forcing
public investors to push more money into already public stocks, because they have no other outlet for the money they wish to invest in technology.
Thus raising the public tech shares even higher.</p>

<h2 id="so-whats-the-solution">So what’s the solution?</h2>
<p>There is currently no way for the general public to offer investments in to these private, smaller, faster-growing companies.  By the time these companies
do go public, the opportunity for huge growth has already passed by, and the general public misses out.  No true solution exists.  The best way to be 
sure to not lose money is not to bet, but that’s like saying the best way to not die in a car accident is not go outside.  I can’t offer a solution but
evidence and analysis of a problem could potentially help some others discover a better strategy than the continual bidding up of the same Big Co Tech Stocks.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
